[theme music playing]
[laughs]
[Julio] Even if you
and your mother join forces,
the authorities seized all her assets.
Clearly, Papa, you underestimated Mama.
What the police have
is only the tip of the iceberg.
You know, Red Dragon is more
than what meets the eye.
I will inherit everything Red Dragon owns.
All the things that you see and you don't.
[Emilia laughing]
[Diego] Looks like it'll
be hard to get in.
This place is heavily guarded.
We'll need help from the cops.
[Lily] First, we have to make sure
that Red Dragon's money
really is in there.
[Julio] You and I have a
common enemy. Lily Cruz.
What if I can tell you
that I can offer you
that alliance against Lily Cruz,
and, most importantly, that I can
guarantee your freedom?
[Emilia] You shouldn't fall for
Papa's trap, you know?
I have a feeling
he needs something from you.
Break time's over. Back to your posts now.
[Lily] It won't be easy to get
to Helena's hidden wealth.
We have to use force. We need manpower.
Leave it to me.
[Lily] Myla is gone.
She was the only one left
who could testify for us.
How can I file the case again,
if I don't have anyone
who can testify for me?
I'll testify against Red Dragon.
[Helena] Today, justice is served.
I am not Red Dragon.
And no one can prove I am
that wicked crime leader.
[Lily] Everything I did was for nothing.
Marlon, what about Lily?
[sighs] Let's just give her some space.
She needs some time alone.
[somber music playing]
Jepoy.
[door opening]
Lily.
[Camia sniffles]
What else do I have to do, Mom?
I've done everything I can.
I put Arnaldo in prison…
And Emilia too.
I took Julio's power from him.
And I put Red Dragon behind bars.
But what happened?!
Where did all my effort end up?!
Where?
It all went down the drain.
Lily. I know you did everything you could.
You did everything and more.
So never question your capabilities.
I know!
I don't want to do that, but I have to!
I don't want to give up,
but it's just so exhausting!
Our plans all end up in smoke!
Too many people have sacrificed
so much for this!
Including their lives! But for what?
After I have them locked up,
they'll walk out Scot-free
after a few days.
We exhaust all our efforts
to bring them to justice,
and for what? So we can sit here
and watch them walk away
like nothing happened.
I don't want to give up.
[tense music playing]
[sobbing]
But I'm losing faith
that we can find justice, Mom.
Does justice even exist?
Because I don't think it does.
That's what I feel now.
Justice does not exist.
Because all those criminals
can just use their money to bend the law.
What do I have to do?
What more should I do?
Do the Ardientes want me
to punish them myself
and take justice into my own hands?
If that's what they want…
then may Dad forgive me,
but I might just give it to them.
Lily,
since the start we knew that
defeating the enemy wouldn't be easy.
But, no matter how many times we fall,
we always get back up again.
We continue to fight,
and that's what matters.
Your father died to make way
for Lily Cruz.
A Lily Cruz who's ready
to fight for the people.
Because you're the only one
who can take the Ardientes down.
Just you.
Lily, get up.
Get up.
Now isn't the time to give up.
Keep fighting, Lily. Keep fighting!
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
[breathes deeply]
It keeps draining me,
but I'll keep fighting, Mom.
We won't lose hope.
Because the people of Ardiente
haven't lost hope either.
And, I'm going to make
their dream come true.
["Wildflower" instrumental
continues playing]
Where should I take you, ma'am?
To the place where I truly belong.
Put it there first.
Replace that. Is that good?
-Magbanua.
-Governor.
I want you to keep the gates open.
You know the drill.
[chuckles] And you, my grandson,
stay in my office until it's time.
Got you, Gramps. See you.
And what are you two whispering about?
Nothing. Um…
it's a good thing you're here.
Um… at least, the family's complete.
What's going on, Papa?
Why do you have this?
Oh, um… one more thing.
I'd like you to put
on your best couture dress
because it's showtime.
This is going to be some night.
[slow tense music playing]
We're live at the Ardiente residence,
where a very special guest
from the first family
of Poblacion Ardiente has arrived.
Tonight, the guest of honor
is the light of Julio and Emilia's home.
The light of our town.
The one and only, Ms. Helena Montoya.
[tense music playing]
[shutters clicking]
It's a family reunion for all ages,
so stay tuned, everyone,
and let us all join the Ardiente family.
[tense music continues playing]
A very good evening to all of you.
[Julio] Let me just say,
our gathering this evening
is an important event.
Because for the first time,
we will be dining with my beloved…
Helena.
The lovely Helena.
This just proves that the greatest gift
that we can receive during the holidays
is knowing our families are whole.
A family that we must defend
fight for, and protect
against malicious people
who aim to tear it down.
As you all know,
for over a century,
it was the Ardiente family
that took care of,
showed love to, and raised all of you.
And we've proven our love to you
through our excessive contributions
to infrastructure, education,
land, and housing.
And, of course,
only the best from
your beloved Governor Julio.
It's sad to think that we have
opponents lurking around…
who want to involve our family
in crimes we had nothing to do with.
First of all, they attempted
to bring down my grandson,
Mayor Arnaldo.
Unfortunately, he can't be with us tonight
because he is still recovering.
After that,
they proceeded to target
my beloved daughter, Emilia.
They tried to imprison her
with charges that have no basis.
But they weren't content with that,
so they attacked me next.
They attempted to overthrow me
as the governor of this province.
Their immorality knows no bounds.
And now, they focused
their eyes on Helena.
And just like Emilia,
they accused her of crimes
without any basis.
Now, let me ask you.
Would you allow those people
to ruin your family
whose only aim is to serve you
and ensure your welfare and safety?
Of course not. Especially now
he's back with Helena Montoya.
Wow! They have such a great family.
They should be our role models, right?
What a liar! They're frauds!
He should've said that a family of killers
and thieves have been reunited.
I still think that Helena is Red Dragon.
The Governor just found a way to free her.
Well, good luck to all of us.
It's hopeless.
Corruption and murder are here to stay.
Those are what the Ardientes are good at.
You said it!
Be scared of the Ardientes
if you're a criminal,
but if not, you'll be protected.
And they're great leaders.
I mean, you all saw the new
bridge they constructed, right?
The Ardientes do nothing
but help us. Viva Ardiente!
[everyone] Viva Ardiente!
I have great faith
that you will join and help us
in fighting these nuisances.
You know what they say,
"Those who scream the loudest,
are usually the ones
with the most to hide."
With that said,
could these people be the ones
who are truly responsible
for the crimes they're accusing
our family of?
So for that reason,
we should unite…
to defend and fight for
our beloved province.
Viva Ardiente!
-[all] Viva Ardiente!
-[crowd clapping]
You were right, Mom.
[tense music playing]
I'm the only one
who can topple the Ardientes.
I'll take justice into my own hands.
If it's a fight that they want,
then I'll give it to them
with the punishment they all deserve.
[tense music swells]
[Julio] Well, thank you very
much to all of you for coming.
It was a pleasure for us.
-Thank you so much.
-Thank you. Merry Christmas.
-Viva Ardiente!
-[everyone] Viva Ardiente!
Thank you. Let us see you all out.
Bye. Good night.
Good night. Remember to drive safely.
Night.
Be careful on your way home.
-[Arnaldo clapping]
-[ominous music playing]
And the best ensemble goes to…
the Ardiente family.
-[Julio and Arnaldo chuckle]
-Great acting, everyone.
Thank you.
How the hell did it happen, huh?
Emilia.
Mama, you told me
that no matter what happens,
you will never accept any help from Papa.
But here you are,
allying yourself with him.
Shut your mouth, Emilia.
Look. I helped your mother
get out of prison.
Do you have a problem with that?
How?
[knocking on door]
[suspenseful music playing]
[thuds]
[grunts]
Pick one, your call. Money or your life?
[tense music playing]
I don't plan on dying yet.
[scoffs]
THERE'S A HOUSE FOR YOU IN BITAC.
DON'T COME BACK HERE AGAIN.
[Mateo] Let go of me! Let me go!
[grunts]
[Mateo panting]
[Mateo] Julio Ardiente.
Why are you doing this to me?
I didn't betray Red Dragon.
But then, you betrayed me.
[grunts]
You know, Mateo.
You are a wild card.
You can betray Red Dragon solely
because of your hatred for me.
I know that.
[grunts]
Julio Ardiente, I won't do that.
Why are you doing this?
Mateo. Don't you see how
magnanimous I'm trying to be?
I'm giving you a chance to live!
Leave Poblacion Ardiente
and never look back!
Because if you do, the only
welcoming party you'll get
is a bullet from me.
Hasta la vista, Señor.
I told you never to get on my bad side.
[Mateo grunts]
Judge Lustre already did
a huge favor for you.
What you're asking for
is no easy task, Julio.
How about this?
Is a billion pesos asking nicely enough?
I'm pretty sure you used
the people's money
to pay off that judge, Papa.
Now, I want to know, how do you
plan on giving it back?
I don't plan on giving a single cent back.
But, I expect Helena to pay me
as a form of gratitude for my efforts
in getting her out of prison.
I mean, one billion pesos
isn't much for her, anyway.
That's right, Julio.
That amount isn't much for me.
And one day, I'll pay you
back down to the last cent.
-What?
-Oh, is that so?
Well then, we'll carry on
with this charade
until you've paid me no less
than one billion pesos in cash.
In the meantime, we'll have to keep on
making the people think
we're one big happy family.
-Ew.
-[Julio chuckles]
-Why?
-Well, Julio.
-Yes?
-You've got me where you want me.
-Disgusting. I'm leaving.
-I'm not going anywhere.
Stop whispering in my ear.
Flirt!
What?
-Ah… nothing.
-Nothing, really?
I don't like that look on your face.
[Arnaldo chuckles]
What are you trying to…
What are you trying to imply?
Huh?
I'm just saying we have a plan.
[suspenseful music playing]
Boss Jaguar,
Red Dragon and the Ardientes
are working together now.
Are you sure Red Dragon and Helena Montoya
are the same person?
Come on. It's like you
don't know the Ardientes.
I bet the governor already
cleared Helena Montoya's name
so that when the time comes,
they'll be on the same side.
What's your plan now, Boss Jaguar?
The Ardientes have become more powerful
with Red Dragon on their side.
Our operations are at risk here.
I mean, we're nothing compared
to that enormous group.
Boss, shouldn't we be
joining their group now?
[tense music playing]
This group was formed to take
on the Ardientes.
So, don't you worry.
We'll bring them down.
[pensive music playing]
[Lily] I know you bombed my properties!
An eye for an eye, Red Dragon.
The jig is up because right now,
everyone knows that Helena Montoya
is none other than Red Dragon.
[helicopter blades whirring]
Got you.
Caught you red-handed, Red Dragon.
["Hindi Kita Iiwan" playing]
[knocking]
You know, when I was a kid…
people would pick fights
and gang up on me.
Then, I met this little girl.
She was beautiful, smart, and most of all,
brave.
She taught me how to fight back.
Lily…
You have to be strong.
And I'm right here.
Even if the whole world
conspires against you,
I'll stay and stand up to them with you.
Just the two of us.
["Hindi Kita Iiwan" continues playing]
[ominous music playing]
Damn those Ardientes.
Damn every one of them.
My daughter has gone through so much.
She's risked her whole life
to capture them.
As her mother, I feel so helpless,
like I can't do anything for her.
But I won't let her see that, Damian.
Because what she needs now,
is a mother who's ready
to fight by her side,
no matter what happens.
I'm here for Lily too.
I'll be here for both of you,
no matter what.
[tense music playing]
Emilia, let's talk for a sec.
-Emilia, stop, we need to talk.
-What now?!
It's not like there's
anything else to talk about.
Yes, there is!
Just what am I to this family, huh?
You've been keeping me out of the loop!
I had to find out that your
mother was Red Dragon on my own
when you could've just told me.
So, why didn't you?
Well, Raul, have you ever done
anything to prove
your worth to this family? You haven't!
You are a liability, Raul.
So, just shut up because
it's not like you're doing
anything useful at all.
Looks like your father's
pestering your mother again.
And why is that?
Well, even all of Ardiente
knows just how much money
is involved now
that your grandmother
and I have joined forces.
[scoffs]
And let me guess,
he wants a piece of the pie.
[Julio chuckles]
Exactly. Your father wants
to get a cut of that money.
He wants to have his own little share.
But I can't let that happen.
He's nothing but a nuisance.
Which means we have to make sure
that the money stays between us.
So, we better do something about it
before he manages to outwit
your poor mother again.
Okay. I'm… I'm game. What's the plan?
[chuckles]
[Raul] You can't fool me.
I'll find out about your plans
one way or another, you bastards.
[tense music playing]
We couldn't get the court
to release a search warrant.
What?
Wasn't the evidence we presented enough?
Have they gone blind?
Helena Montoya's hidden wealth
is right there.
There's nothing we can do.
All her accounts are clean.
And I can only move
with the judge's permission.
Judge?
Don't you realize that
the Ardientes have all the courts
in the palm of their hands?
So, if you're just going
to let yourselves be used,
then what else are you here for?
I am not a vigilante.
It's my job to make sure
the law is enforced,
regardless of how I feel about it.
Enough.
It's fine, Agent Salonga.
I'll just give you another call.
[vehicle starting]
[car engine revving]
I bet the Ardientes found out
that we're after
Helena Montoya's hidden wealth.
Now, they're going to secure her wealth.
What do we do if they succeed?
I'm not part of
Red Dragon's syndicate anymore.
There's still one thing we can try, Diego.
There's no way I'm letting the
Ardientes get all that money.
Truth is, those were funds
stolen from the people.
And now, I bet they're going to
use that money to stay in power.
So, if the law enforcers
can't do anything about it,
then I guess
we'll have to do things my way.
[tense music playing]
-Stay right there, sir.
-Wait, I just want to talk to…
Hey, why won't you let me?!
Out of my way! Now!
[grunts]
[Colonel Magbanua]
Give me a reason to shoot!
Papa, why are you doing this?
Raul.
-[Raul panting]
-Bring him closer to me.
Raul, quit playing dumb already.
I know you're bothering us
because you want to get
a share of the money we'll be getting.
What the hell are you talking about?
I don't care about that!
This is what I don't like about you.
You're insulting my intelligence.
There's too much money
at stake here for a moron
like you to get involved.
So from this day forward,
I'm disowning you,
which means you no longer have
anything to do with my family!
Well, it looks like I need to remind you,
that there's no way that's happening
because, first of all,
I'm your daughter's husband.
And that boy over there
is my son. Your grandson.
Mhm. I'm aware.
Besides, you know you owe a lot to my dad.
You're an ungrateful bastard.
You know that?
Actually, that's really
the only thing you have on me.
Didn't I tell you I should've
finished you off ages ago?
Except I owed a great deal to your father,
and that's the only reason
why you're still alive.
But, I can also have you killed
right this very second.
Because, first of all,
you're a worthless husband.
And, you're a useless father
to this amazing boy over here,
who just happens to be related to you.
That said, no one's going to
care if I have you killed.
Because no one gives a damn about you!
[grunts]
Remember this, you bastard.
I almost died that day
because of what you did!
-I know.
-And I've never forgotten!
So this is my revenge!
[tense music playing]
Now, scram!
You're lucky I still know
how to respect my elders.
Well, you better.
-Let's go!
-[Julio] You worthless moron!
Let go of me!
-[Arnaldo giggling]
-What a blockhead.
He makes my blood boil.
[Raul] Your dad was right, Raul.
You threw your life away choosing Emilia.
You stuck with her family
because you wanted a share of their power.
Because you're a loser. A loser!
Helena and her cheap tactics!
I know she has the money,
but she keeps playing coy.
Well, if that's the case, she's smooth.
She's discreetly trying to outsmart you.
[Julio grunts]
But…
I know how you can get even.
I know what you're implying. I know.
The problem is,
we don't know the exact location
of the damn treasure.
Okay.
Who's the person
that grandma trusts the most?
Isn't it Mom?
-Yeah.
-Now think about this.
Who does Mom trust the most?
You.
Emilia, my dear.
Let's get this over with, shall we?
I know something's bothering you,
but I don't know what it is.
What is it? Tell me.
As if you have no idea
why I'm bothered, Mama.
I'm sure the decision you made
kept you up all night.
I know I may have made a deal
with the devil.
And I know that your Papa
is not to be trusted.
I only did that to get out of jail.
And now that I'm free,
it only means that we can go on
with our plans to rebuild my kingdom.
You and me, together. Isn't that great?
[sighs] I'm just here
to protect you, Mama.
Because I have a strong feeling
that Papa will double-cross you.
I know that he's not to be trusted.
That's why now,
I'm going to make you the
protector of my hidden wealth.
I want you to go to the site.
Do everything that you can.
Check the security. Do whatever you can.
Just guard it with your life.
[Arnaldo] Having said that,
the only way to the treasure
is through Grandma's princess.
So, I'll keep an eye on them.
-Mom, specifically.
-No, no, no, no, no.
I don't want them
to lose their trust in you.
I want you to go on spying,
but not on them.
Instead, you should keep
your eyes on Lily's group.
I know the right person
who can spy on your mother.
[suspenseful music playing]
[scoffs]
I know.
Okay. Well, in case you change
your mind, I'm here.
[chuckles] I… love it, Mama!
But, um, can I ask help
from my one and only protector?
Who?
My pet cat, Jaguar.
I'm sorry, Emilia. No.
But… but why?
You might end up with the wrong
Jaguar, the original Jaguar.
Well, that's better, Mama,
because he's one of your men.
We can't trust him.
There's a lot of things
you don't know about him.
Well, if that's the case, Mama,
why don't you
just have him killed, like what you did
to a certain traitor
who tried to go against me?
Because the original Jaguar
has connections
with our enemies. I can still use him.
Soon, you will understand
what I'm talking about.
But, for now, you have got to trust me.
[suspenseful music playing]
Just as we planned,
we'll go through the back.
But, once we get our hands
on Helena's fortune,
we can't surrender it to the authorities.
The Ardientes are in power,
and I'm sure they'd all just get it back.
All right. We won't surrender it.
We'll destroy all of Helena
Montoya's brothels,
remaining firearms,
and other illegal businesses
that are corrupting the town of Ardiente.
We'll destroy all of it.
[tense music swells]
Okay, I'll see you later, Anna.
-Sure.
-Good night.
Take care.
[crickets chirping]
Anna, can we talk?
I know I made a mistake.
And, I want to ask for your forgiveness.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
[dramatic music playing]
Please give me another chance.
Anna, talk to me. I'm going crazy here.
There's nothing else to talk about.
Anna, wait.
Is this it for us?
Anna, I know I hurt you. [breathes deeply]
And that's why I want to apologize.
Besides, what's up with that?
I'm gone for one second
and now you have Marlon?
What on earth are you
talking about, Jepoy?
Marlon and I are just friends.
And besides, you of all people
should know you don't have
the right to ask anymore.
That you don't have the right
to care about my decisions
because we're through.
Anna, I loved you.
And, I still do, so please forgive me.
Give me another--
Love?! You should've thought of that
while you were enjoying yourself
with Natalie.
Because if you really loved me,
you wouldn't have done that, Jepoy.
You wouldn't have been able
to hurt me like that.
Sorry. Anna, sorry.
I'm sorry.
I am too, Lily.
I know you really need my support,
but I have to stay in town for now.
I understand.
[somber music playing]
I thought you and Anna
just had a small disagreement.
But it was actually pretty serious.
Jepoy, I think you know
that what you did was wrong
on every level,
so you need to be more patient.
You should get some rest.
Come back when you're ready.
I'm going to need you
for when we fight again.
And when I say "get some rest",
that doesn't mean with other women.
I hope that's clear.
Now, go.
[sighs] I've done everything
I can to help my daughter.
[breathes deeply]
But it never ends.
And, this battle is wearing
my daughter down.
But, I hope…
I hope you can give me the
strength to keep supporting her.
I wish there was still something
I could do for her.
I wish I could find another way to help.
[dramatic music playing]
Jepoy, be careful, okay?
Make sure no civilian gets hurt
when you get to the armory
and the brothel.
I will. You can count on me.
We'll make Helena regret
she ever got out of prison.
All right, go. Text me once you get there.
Got it.
[Lily] Take care.
[Jepoy] Let's go.
[car engine starting]
-Let's go too.
-Lily…
Mom.
Lily.
Even though I want to stop you,
I already know you've made up your mind.
So, I'll be praying for you.
Thank you, Mom.
[dramatic music playing]
[Damian] I shouldn't
swear to protect just Camia.
I have to help Lily and Diego too.
-Please be careful.
-I will, Mom.
And, I promise I'll come back to you.
You should get back inside.
Uncle Damian…
please take care of my mother.
-Diego.
-Auntie.
Bye, Mom.
Are you ready?
I'd fight all alone if I could.
[sighs] I wouldn't let you.
From now on,
we'll face every single challenge
in our lives together.
I'll always be by your side.
You're right, Diego.
We'll face everything together.
Just the two of us.
So no matter what happens,
always remember how much I love you.
I love you too, Diego.
[romantic music playing]
[Emilia] I'll make sure
that even the devil himself
won't be able to find
or steal your fortune.
Very good.
Now get me my money.
[Diego] Isn't that Magbanua?
What are Julio's men doing here?
[Lily] Diego, we can't let the Ardientes
take Helena's fortune first.
[Arnaldo] By the way, where's Lily?
They said they would take down
all of Red Dragon's businesses.
They'll try to look
for her hidden wealth too.
[Lily] That's where Red Dragon
hides her fortune.
[man] Looks like we have visitors.
We should get more men.
No need.
It's time to give them my little surprise.
-[Lily screams]
-[alarms blaring]
[theme music playing]